<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>6502 on The 8-bit Zine</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/categories/6502/</link><description>Recent content in 6502 on The 8-bit Zine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 11:00:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the8bitzine.github.io/categories/6502/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Atari 2600 - the console that started it all</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/11/atari-2600-the-console-that-started-it-all/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/11/atari-2600-the-console-that-started-it-all/</guid><description>The Atari 2600, originally called VCS, was my first game console. Officially produced for almost fifteen years (much longer, considering eastern fakes), the machine was one of the first consoles to use a cartridge as a game carrier. Perhaps, as the first one, it used the 6502 processor (or rather, its trimmed version - 6507).
It only had 128 bytes (yes, bytes) of RAM. The graphics chip allowed to generate graphics with a resolution of 40 x 192 px, although an efficient programmer was able to squeeze 160 x 192 px.</description></item><item><title>From zero to 6502 assembly - how to teach yourself programming</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/from-zero-to-6502-assembly-how-to-teach-yourself-programming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 09:55:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/from-zero-to-6502-assembly-how-to-teach-yourself-programming/</guid><description>Assembly language, this term alone raises mixed feelings. We admire programmers who write in low-level languages, and sometimes we see a bit of superhuman in them. Often, beginner (and even advanced) programmers are concerned about assembly languages. This also applies to me. I was never interested in programming 8-bit computers because I thought that BASIC was quite limited, and the 6502 assembly was a field completely beyond my intellectual abilities.</description></item><item><title>Atari 65XE The 8 bit computer of The Eastern Bloc</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/atari-65xe-the-8-bit-computer-of-the-eastern-bloc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/atari-65xe-the-8-bit-computer-of-the-eastern-bloc/</guid><description>The Commodore 64 is the most popular personal computer of all time to this day. In the 1980s, however, the world was divided by the Iron Curtain, and things were fundamentally different on the socialist side of Europe. The Commodore 64 was not available in the countries of the Eastern Bloc. Here market was dominated by the Soviet clones Sinclair machines and&amp;hellip; Atari 65XE.
In 1984, after leaving Commodore, Jack Tramel bought Atari.</description></item><item><title>5 NES games (including hidden gems) I would take on a desert island</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/5-nes-games-including-hidden-gems-i-would-take-on-a-desert-island/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:55:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/5-nes-games-including-hidden-gems-i-would-take-on-a-desert-island/</guid><description>Have you ever thought about minimizing your game collection, so you would have only titles which you absolutely love? It may be an interesting idea if you think about it. Here is my „Top 5” but order does not matter, since every game is different and unique.
DR. MARIO
A highly addictive game (like drugs). This, published in 1990, tetris-like title will keep you hooked for hours and hours. Gameplay requires a little bit of creative thinking, but first and foremost – I find it very relaxing.</description></item></channel></rss>