<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The 8-bit Zine</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on The 8-bit Zine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 11:15:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the8bitzine.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Commodore VIC-20 - when computers found their way home</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2022/02/commodore-vic-20-when-computers-found-their-way-home/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 11:15:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2022/02/commodore-vic-20-when-computers-found-their-way-home/</guid><description>The VIC-20 was the first home computer produced by Commodore.
The history of the VIC-20 begins in 1977, when MOS Technologies, already part of Commodore, developed the 6560 graphics chip (the PAL-6561 version was sold in Europe) called VIC (short for video interface chip). Soon the design process began at Commodore, or rather the search for a design for their first home computer, which was to be presented at CES in 1980.</description></item><item><title>Space Flight by Paul Lutus</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2022/02/space-flight-by-paul-lutus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 14:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2022/02/space-flight-by-paul-lutus/</guid><description>This &amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo; simulator was writen around 1972 and published in 1977 - long before open source movement came to existance and a little bit before it&amp;rsquo;s author got his first computer. And it runs (flies?) on a scientific calculator with a segment-display.
Paul Lutus has become a legend among computer enthusiasts thanks to his brilliant career from a self-taught electronics technician to a NASA engineer. He is also a programmer who was the first one to work remotely in the 1970s.</description></item><item><title>KETTU 512 XE - Raspberry Pi handheld computer for retrogaming</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/12/kettu-512-xe-raspberry-pi-handheld-computer-for-retrogaming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 14:10:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/12/kettu-512-xe-raspberry-pi-handheld-computer-for-retrogaming/</guid><description>KETTU 512 XE is my homemade computer for retrogaming which I built with a Raspberry Pi Zero and ice cream sticks. The inspiration was the Polish computer kit CA-80 and the name refers to my favourite home computer Atari 65 XE. The word kettu means fox in Finnish language.
I replaced the default Retro Pie ascii art. The Need When I left my country, I left behind many things, including all my computers and laptops.</description></item><item><title>Curse of the Azure Bonds - AD&amp;D for retro computers</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/11/curse-of-the-azure-bonds-add-for-retro-computers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 18:10:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/11/curse-of-the-azure-bonds-add-for-retro-computers/</guid><description>I recently moved out and left behind my D&amp;amp;D books and a large collection of Magic The Gathering cards. So for several weeks I was looking for an interesting computer RPG. Ideally, set in the D&amp;amp;D world and one in which battles would be played in a mode similar to Final Fantasy Tactics. The obvious prerequisite for this was that it was an eight or 16 bit era game so that I could run it on my retro gaming gear.</description></item><item><title>M.U.L.E. - Starcraft of the 8-bit era</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/11/m.u.l.e.-starcraft-of-the-8-bit-era/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 11:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/11/m.u.l.e.-starcraft-of-the-8-bit-era/</guid><description>M.U.L.E. is an economic strategy you must have. Many consider it to be the best game ever made for eight-bit computers. I think I agree with that. One of the game&amp;rsquo;s breakthroughs is the availability of multi-player for up to four players.
We start with choosing a colour. The computer displays the next colours, the player can reserve a colour for himself by pressing the fire-button. Then we go to the choice of one of eight available races: Mechtron, Bonzoid, Flapper, Gollumer, Leggite, Packer, Spheroid or Humanoid.</description></item><item><title>Atari 2600 - the console that started it all</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/11/atari-2600-the-console-that-started-it-all/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/11/atari-2600-the-console-that-started-it-all/</guid><description>The Atari 2600, originally called VCS, was my first game console. Officially produced for almost fifteen years (much longer, considering eastern fakes), the machine was one of the first consoles to use a cartridge as a game carrier. Perhaps, as the first one, it used the 6502 processor (or rather, its trimmed version - 6507).
It only had 128 bytes (yes, bytes) of RAM. The graphics chip allowed to generate graphics with a resolution of 40 x 192 px, although an efficient programmer was able to squeeze 160 x 192 px.</description></item><item><title>Overthrown - action game for Commodore VIC-20</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/10/overthrown-action-game-for-commodore-vic-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 11:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/10/overthrown-action-game-for-commodore-vic-20/</guid><description>Palace situation turns grim
crowds chant &amp;ldquo;go away&amp;rdquo;
If I were a dictator, I would take everything valuable and run away. This is exactly what you need to do in the game Overthrown for the Commodore VIC-20.
Some of us remember the times when eight-bit computers were every teenager&amp;rsquo;s dream. Slightly younger ones may remember the classic versions of GTA games, those with simple graphics and a top-down view. Later, 3D graphics almost completely dominated the gaming world.</description></item><item><title>5 Easy project ideas for beginner coders</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/10/5-easy-project-ideas-for-beginner-coders/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 11:40:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/10/5-easy-project-ideas-for-beginner-coders/</guid><description>This article is a continuation of the series dedicated to people who want to start their adventure with programming. If you&amp;rsquo;re just wondering where to start, check out the article: From zero to 6502 assembly - how to teach yourself programming
You have already completed your first programming course. You have gone through the tutorial for the selected language. Furthermore, you analysed all the examples and performed the exercises correctly.</description></item><item><title>MIK CA80 - Arduino of Eastern Bloc</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/10/mik-ca80-arduino-of-eastern-bloc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 13:20:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/10/mik-ca80-arduino-of-eastern-bloc/</guid><description>Even before the microcomputer boom in Europe, enthusiasts were using computer kits that they were assembling themselves. This avant-garde of eight-bit computing seemed primitive compared to popular home computers. However, it was little known computers such as the Sinclair MK-14 that inspired the first bedroom-coders. This post however is about a different computer, unknown on the West, forgotten on the East - MIK CA80, early Polish mikrocomputer.
The history of modern PCs begins in 1970 when an Italian engineer, Federico Faggin, becomes an employee of Intel.</description></item><item><title>Transarctica - ice cold train combat</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/transarctica-ice-cold-train-combat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 13:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/transarctica-ice-cold-train-combat/</guid><description>The world has come to an end, the sun is gone, the earth has turned into an ice desert. In an attempt to save the world from the Greenhouse effect, scientists detonated nuclear charges at both poles of the planet. By doing so, they created a vapour layer in the atmosphere that, instead of cooling the planet down, led to eternal winter. The nightmare of scientists and environmentalists has become a fact.</description></item><item><title>Tracker music without a tracker</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/tracker-music-without-a-tracker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 20:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/tracker-music-without-a-tracker/</guid><description>As a musician, I have always envied demoscene artists the possibility of working with modern software. The graphic artist will prepare the image in Photoshop, than all he needs to do is to use the converter and copy the file to his retro-computer. That&amp;rsquo;s all - art for demoarty is ready. A musician&amp;rsquo;s life is not that easy. Musician has to work with trackers, whether he wants it or not.</description></item><item><title>From zero to 6502 assembly - how to teach yourself programming</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/from-zero-to-6502-assembly-how-to-teach-yourself-programming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 09:55:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/from-zero-to-6502-assembly-how-to-teach-yourself-programming/</guid><description>Assembly language, this term alone raises mixed feelings. We admire programmers who write in low-level languages, and sometimes we see a bit of superhuman in them. Often, beginner (and even advanced) programmers are concerned about assembly languages. This also applies to me. I was never interested in programming 8-bit computers because I thought that BASIC was quite limited, and the 6502 assembly was a field completely beyond my intellectual abilities.</description></item><item><title>Atari 65XE The 8 bit computer of The Eastern Bloc</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/atari-65xe-the-8-bit-computer-of-the-eastern-bloc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/atari-65xe-the-8-bit-computer-of-the-eastern-bloc/</guid><description>The Commodore 64 is the most popular personal computer of all time to this day. In the 1980s, however, the world was divided by the Iron Curtain, and things were fundamentally different on the socialist side of Europe. The Commodore 64 was not available in the countries of the Eastern Bloc. Here market was dominated by the Soviet clones Sinclair machines and&amp;hellip; Atari 65XE.
In 1984, after leaving Commodore, Jack Tramel bought Atari.</description></item><item><title>5 NES games (including hidden gems) I would take on a desert island</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/5-nes-games-including-hidden-gems-i-would-take-on-a-desert-island/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:55:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/5-nes-games-including-hidden-gems-i-would-take-on-a-desert-island/</guid><description>Have you ever thought about minimizing your game collection, so you would have only titles which you absolutely love? It may be an interesting idea if you think about it. Here is my „Top 5” but order does not matter, since every game is different and unique.
DR. MARIO
A highly addictive game (like drugs). This, published in 1990, tetris-like title will keep you hooked for hours and hours. Gameplay requires a little bit of creative thinking, but first and foremost – I find it very relaxing.</description></item><item><title>1K ZX Chess – a tiny game</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/1k-zx-chess-a-tiny-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 11:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/1k-zx-chess-a-tiny-game/</guid><description>The ZX81 was one of the first 8-bit computers, in its basic version it had only 1KB of RAM. Nevertheless, it has thousands of games and programs in the form of both listings and applications distributed on tapes. The machine could be expanded with modules extending the available memory up to 64 KB. From today&amp;rsquo;s perspective, it is fascinating how much could be squeezed out of the basic 1KB version.</description></item><item><title>Goddes of Fuji – Numen for an 8-bit Atari</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/goddes-of-fuji-numen-for-an-8-bit-atari/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 13:55:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/goddes-of-fuji-numen-for-an-8-bit-atari/</guid><description>Numen by Taquart! That’s a perfect topic for the first article. Numen (Latin word for goddes) debuted in 2002 at Polish demoparty „Lato ludzików”, it took first place in demo compo. Earliest and most technologically advanced part of this demo was made already in 1997 (authors called it „Turbo vectys” and it presents 3D blocks in last part).
But what it actually is? Imagine if Atari could run Doom – surrealistic, psychedelic version of Doom.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 13:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/about/</guid><description>The 8-bit Zine The 8-bit Zine is a blog about retro computers, vintage games, demoscene and digital art of the bygone era. It was born of the need to share passion. For me, it is a place where I gather information about my favourite computers, consoles, games, demos and all creativity related to 8 and 16-bit computers. I make every effort to prepare good texts, but if you see that the information is incorrect or incomplete, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss it in the comments.</description></item></channel></rss>