<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programs on The 8-bit Zine</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/categories/programs/</link><description>Recent content in Programs on The 8-bit Zine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 13:55:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the8bitzine.github.io/categories/programs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Transarctica - ice cold train combat</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/transarctica-ice-cold-train-combat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 13:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/transarctica-ice-cold-train-combat/</guid><description>The world has come to an end, the sun is gone, the earth has turned into an ice desert. In an attempt to save the world from the Greenhouse effect, scientists detonated nuclear charges at both poles of the planet. By doing so, they created a vapour layer in the atmosphere that, instead of cooling the planet down, led to eternal winter. The nightmare of scientists and environmentalists has become a fact.</description></item><item><title>Tracker music without a tracker</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/tracker-music-without-a-tracker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 20:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/tracker-music-without-a-tracker/</guid><description>As a musician, I have always envied demoscene artists the possibility of working with modern software. The graphic artist will prepare the image in Photoshop, than all he needs to do is to use the converter and copy the file to his retro-computer. That&amp;rsquo;s all - art for demoarty is ready. A musician&amp;rsquo;s life is not that easy. Musician has to work with trackers, whether he wants it or not.</description></item><item><title>1K ZX Chess – a tiny game</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/1k-zx-chess-a-tiny-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 11:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/1k-zx-chess-a-tiny-game/</guid><description>The ZX81 was one of the first 8-bit computers, in its basic version it had only 1KB of RAM. Nevertheless, it has thousands of games and programs in the form of both listings and applications distributed on tapes. The machine could be expanded with modules extending the available memory up to 64 KB. From today&amp;rsquo;s perspective, it is fascinating how much could be squeezed out of the basic 1KB version.</description></item></channel></rss>