<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on The 8-bit Zine</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on The 8-bit Zine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:00:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://the8bitzine.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Atari 65XE The 8 bit computer of The Eastern Bloc</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/atari-65xe-the-8-bit-computer-of-the-eastern-bloc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:00:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/atari-65xe-the-8-bit-computer-of-the-eastern-bloc/</guid><description>The Commodore 64 is the most popular personal computer of all time to this day. In the 1980s, however, the world was divided by the Iron Curtain, and things were fundamentally different on the socialist side of Europe. The Commodore 64 was not available in the countries of the Eastern Bloc. Here market was dominated by the Soviet clones Sinclair machines and&amp;hellip; Atari 65XE.
In 1984, after leaving Commodore, Jack Tramel bought Atari.</description></item><item><title>From zero to 6502 assembly - how to teach yourself programming</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/from-zero-to-6502-assembly-how-to-teach-yourself-programming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 10:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/from-zero-to-6502-assembly-how-to-teach-yourself-programming/</guid><description>Assembly language, this term alone raises mixed feelings. We admire programmers who write in low-level languages, and sometimes we see a bit of superhuman in them. Often, beginner (and even advanced) programmers are concerned about assembly languages. This also applies to me. I was never interested in programming 8-bit computers because I thought that BASIC was quite limited, and the 6502 assembly was a field completely beyond my intellectual abilities.</description></item><item><title>5 NES games (including hidden gems) I would take on a desert island</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/5-nes-games-including-hidden-gems-i-would-take-on-a-desert-island/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:55:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/5-nes-games-including-hidden-gems-i-would-take-on-a-desert-island/</guid><description>Have you ever thought about minimizing your game collection, so you would have only titles which you absolutely love? It may be an interesting idea if you think about it. Here is my „Top 5” but order does not matter, since every game is different and unique.
DR. MARIO
A highly addictive game (like drugs). This, published in 1990, tetris-like title will keep you hooked for hours and hours. Gameplay requires a little bit of creative thinking, but first and foremost – I find it very relaxing.</description></item><item><title>1K ZX Chess – a tiny game</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/1k-zx-chess-a-tiny-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 11:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/1k-zx-chess-a-tiny-game/</guid><description>The ZX81 was one of the first 8-bit computers, in its basic version it had only 1KB of RAM. Nevertheless, it has thousands of games and programs in the form of both listings and applications distributed on tapes. The machine could be expanded with modules extending the available memory up to 64 KB. From today&amp;rsquo;s perspective, it is fascinating how much could be squeezed out of the basic 1KB version.</description></item><item><title>Goddes of Fuji – Numen for an 8-bit Atari</title><link>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/goddes-of-fuji-numen-for-an-8-bit-atari/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 13:55:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://the8bitzine.github.io/2021/09/goddes-of-fuji-numen-for-an-8-bit-atari/</guid><description>Numen by Taquart! That’s a perfect topic for the first article. Numen (Latin word for goddes) debuted in 2002 at Polish demoparty „Lato ludzików”, it took first place in demo compo. Earliest and most technologically advanced part of this demo was made already in 1997 (authors called it „Turbo vectys” and it presents 3D blocks in last part).
But what it actually is? Imagine if Atari could run Doom – surrealistic, psychedelic version of Doom.</description></item></channel></rss>